if anyone who's predicting what looks
like in a year or two is going to be
fundamentally wrong. And I think that
that's really what that makes it so
exciting. We don't know where we're
going other than that we do know that
we're going to keep building software
while maintaining billions if not
trillions of lines of code that are
already out there. We go back a year
into December 2024. Who would have
predicted that at the end of 2025
developers are back in the terminal with
cloud code and and Gemini CLI and Codex
CLI and copile CLI and have like six or
eight or whatever a grid of terminals
open and have all these agents running
in parallel and trying to figure out all
the work of the last 30 commits and what
have you.
when I think about innovation, you know,
from incumbents on it. Copilot is
actually like GitHub copilot is a very
kind of is a great example of innovation
that came from sort of within the
company uh and kind of like pioneered
that sort of new space of of of coding
assistant that feels like an AI tools
now sort of you know like the the old
pattern but you know for a while was
there. Um and then like even with all of
all of its reach and all of its sort of
strength, there was uh like the
opportunity for cursor I guess kind of
most notably to you know copilot
continue to thrive. So it wasn't really
like at the expense of sort of copilot
but but but from a like a market share
perspective you know kind of grow even
faster right and sort of take up that
sort of space on it. And then indeed you
have the disruption coming from
anthropic which is kind of hard to think
about them. Are they a startup? Are they
incumbents? Like th those are very weird
beasts. the sort of the open AI and
anthropic that are like especially
anthropic like sort of a short-lived
organization and a massively valued
organization uh but still very much a
startup in uh in many ways um and you
know overhauls like the the fundamentals
of it's going to be terminal versus ID
um so I guess there's a there there's a
sort of a a faith or still a perspective
that when you're looking to disrupt like
I I I believe that especially when
you're disrupting the way things are
done not not just automating existing
workflows, but rather sort of changing
the way that someone would work. Those
are precisely the places where where
it's hard for an incumbent to kind of
accept it because they have all the
power in the existing way of working. Uh
and so they you know it's sort of it's
hard to accept that that change will
come, right? I think that's the that's
kind of the outside in perspective and
that you look at you know companies that
have been leading uh for a long time and
then are being disrupted or seeing more
competition and you you know feel sad or
worry about the people that are now kind
like in that position that they are no
longer the best in in the market. Um I
think the inside out perspective is
often uh not as um dire as as you may
think you know. Um I I've often thought
when when I work for Mercedes uh that
the best thing that can happen to us is
that BMW announces a new model with a
with a new thing in it uh that the
Mercedes leadership didn't want to fund
and all of a sudden you have an argument
to get to get the funding. Yeah. And and
be able to say okay look our competitors
are doing this we better wake up and um
and and and also you know try to catch
up again. And you you saw in the news
that you know Sam Alman declared a code
red and Google had a coded red and I'm
sure you know SA had um or I not I'm
sure I know SA had a bunch of cordets um
uh over over his his tenure and um and
so competition is good. It actually
makes uh business and it makes life more
fun and we see that everywhere. You know
coming back to my Formula 1 example you
know it was Red Bull that won for four
years and it was Mercedes for like eight
years and then Red Bull had another four
years. you you kind of want these
changes and it motivates those that have
been winning for too long, you know, to
come back and then see how do we now
transform our organization to be a
winner again. And if you you mentioned
cursor and VS code, you know, actually
the IDE space has been phenomenally
stable over the last decade. Like I
remember when I you know started on a
Mac I think was 2008 or 2007 I started
on text mate and and textmate was the
revolution back then and and then as
text made kind of like became stale and
and text made 2 took way too long switch
to sublime edit h and then vs code came
and vs code for the last decade was the
def default uh editor IDE for almost
everybody um there's obviously you know
some emac users and some vim users and
and what have you and now we have you
know real competition again and it's not
only curs versa and VS code with with
co-pilot uh vinsurf is obviously in the
play now recently uh Google anti-gravity
came out uh there's a kilo code and ko
and zed and and so there's a hu
competition and that means somebody sees
an opportunity there to to disrupt and
to innovate and and ultimately build a a
sustainable business and I think that
really is exciting and not something to
to worry about both as the incumbent and
as a disruptor.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, I I I agree and I'm not
sort of worried about it. In fact, I I
like the changes. I think like a uh it
all of these require a moment of
disruption that sort of, you know, makes
sense that is that is hard for sort of
the incumbent to follow. And you're
right that it's always like competition
is the the greatest uh motivator uh for
it and the opportunity to drive. And at
GitHub, you know, it pushed us last year
in 2024 um uh uh to go from just provide
having one default model in copilot to
offering multimodel choice um uh where
you know at at GitHub universe in in
November October 2024 I announced that
we now back then you know support uh
claude what was even the version number
clot 3 I think um and Gemini 1.5 pro and
and in the meantime if you if you open
copilot um it has like a whole list of
uh uh u major models and then you can
bring your own model and connect open
router and all these kind of things
right so you can kind of see the direct
impact of competition in the market
leading leading to a better product uh
for the incumbent as well if you look at
Microsoft um it is um probably the uh uh
biggest platform company that is out
there like it's not only copilot and and
github that have some form of you know
neutrality offering offering choice it's
it's also if you look for example on
into Azure foundry U which has like a
huge range of models available. So it's
not just the openi and the the Microsoft
developed models. It's you know mistrial
models and black forest labs models and
lots of open source alternatives and you
can deploy your own model right. So in
that sense u maybe the Switzerland
analogy isn't as good as just saying uh
it's a platform company and platform
companies by design want to have as many
players on top of that platform you know
which is GPU inference as an example or
or you know CPU compute or storage or
what have you in Azure um because that
helps both you know the platform
provider as in Microsoft and you know
the partners all to thrive right I think
that's really the the leverage um that
Microsoft has as a business is the scale
of of that platform
And that's the opportunity for every
startup to become part of, you know,
Microsoft startup program. And I should
ask you, have you actually joined the
Microsoft startup program? And
>> yeah, we're program we're sort of like
in all the programs, right? you know
where uh cuz cuz they all commit until
uh until you get
>> you know at some point every startup
gets kind of especially every B2B
startup maybe less in B2C but B2B every
B2B startups comes to the point where
they either want to leverage Microsoft's
distribution channel and and an amazing
enterprise sales team or or Amazon's or
Google uh because the scale of these
sales teams around the world and their
skill set is is so far ahead of what a
small startup can ever deliver without
going through the pain of you know
building out subsidiaries and building
out local offices and local meetups and
and and you know that there is a lot of
human investment that has to happen that
you can't replace with AI because
enterprise sales fundamentally is still
a you know relationship uh uh
relationship management exercise.